-==http://www.1000fr.com==- 謦灵风软影视论坛荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
www.1000fr.com presents
福尔摩斯探案
The Memoirs Of Sherlock Holmes
-=Keepfrds MNHD Team=- 校对: ptrpan
第七季 第6集
S7E06
硬纸盒案
The Cardboard Box
我并非说制服不适合你 Cushing小姐
I'm not saying the uniform don't suit you, Miss Cushing.
但很高兴看到你没有穿着它来
But it is nice to see you out of it.
Sarah
Sarah!
您肯定是另一位Cushing小姐
You must be the other Miss Cushing.
今天非常开心吧
Isn't this a happy day then, eh,
对于你们三姐妹来说
for all three of you.
是的 是的
Yes' yes it is,
当然是
of course it is.
来了
Just coming!
盗墓贼在伦敦北部大肆作案
Body snatchers strike in north London.
我们在处理一桩现代版的Burk和Hare案吗?
Are we dealing with a modern version
两人是19世纪苏格兰的两个盗墓贼 专门偷尸体卖给爱丁堡医学院做研究用
of Burke and Hare?
不幸的是 在这个时节里解剖学院并不需要
Well, sadly, the anatomy schools
盗墓贼的帮助
don't need the help of body snatchers
他们存了很多从救济院运来的尸体
at this time of the year.
They are well stocked
那你怎么看呢?
with corpses from the poorhouses.
我不知道
What do you think then?
I don't know.
也许是某种古怪的祭礼吧
Some outlandish cult perhaps.
他们就此事咨询过你了吗 福尔摩斯
Have you been consulted on the subject Holmes?
进来 Hawkins
Come on in, Hawkins!
啊哈 Hawkins
Aha Hawkins.
请自便 来点咖啡吧
Make yourself at home.
谢谢
Have a cup of coffee.
你把记录带来了吗
Thank you.
是的 带来了
Have you brought those descriptions?
Yes, yes I have...
现已被挖走的尸体有
Bodies so far exhumed,
Albert Cotter 48岁
Albert Cotter, forty eight.
Shadwell的守鱼人
Fish Porter of Shadwell.
死于心脏病
Heart disease.
Martin Rubery 44岁
Martin Rubery, fifty four.
死于肝硬化
Cirrhosis of the liver.
对他不甚了解
We don't know much about him,
只知道他年轻时曾是一名业余拳击手
except it was thought he was
an amateur pugilist of some sort in his youth.
Jimmy King 39岁
Jimmy King, thirty nine.
女修道院花园看守人
Covent Garden Porter.
死于脑出血
Cerebral hemorrhage
你会继续追查吗
You will continue your researches?
如果您希望这样 福尔摩斯先生
If you say so, Mr. Holmes.
我希望这样
I do say so.
并且盯住一位Murdoch Gull的住所
And keep your eye on the premises
of a certain Murdoch Gull.
什么
Yes?
你认为是Murdoch?
Murdoch, do you think?
他是一切离经叛道的维护者
He's the fence for anything out of the ordinary?
他可能是我们要找的人
He could be our man.
还有一件事 福尔摩斯先生
One more thing, Mr. Holmes.
我们将万分荣幸
The men and I would be very honored
如果圣诞节您愿意来访
if you'd drop by Christmas Eve.
我们将在圣诞节举办一个晚会
We try to get a bit festive at Christmas,
邀请一些客人
and we like to invite a few guests.
圣诞节
Christmas.
Mary?
好了
There.
这才刚开始
It's a start.
Hudson夫人
Mrs Hudson.
福尔摩斯先生?
Mr Holmes?
我该再送华生什么礼物好呢
How am I supposed to
每年这时你都让我头痛
think up yet another present for Watson?
I mean, every year you inflict this agony on me.
很简单 福尔摩斯先生 去Gamages吧
It's quite simple, Mr Holmes, you go to Gamages.
Gamages?
是的 在Holborn 是家百货商店
Yes, it's in Holborn, a departmental store.
百姓商场
The people's Emporium.
你会眼花缭乱的
You will be quite spoilt for ideas.
Gamages
Gamages.
Hudson夫人!
Mrs. Hudson!
你怎么敢拿走我的一叶兰
How dare you take my aspidistra.
我就是敢
I do dare.
下午好 Cushing小姐
Afternoon, Miss Cushing.
节日愉快
Season's Greetings, eh?
下午好 Wilkinson
Good afternoon, Wilkinson.
看起来马上又要下雪
Looks like we're in for a bit more snow before long.
我真希望别下
I do hope not.
这是怎么回事 Jacottet先生
What is this Monsieur Jacottet?
啊 Susan女士
Ah, Madame Susan.
我们已经说好
Our arrangement
你可以在晚饭后坐在客厅火炉旁
is that you may sit by the parlor fire after dinner.
否则 我将非常感激
Otherwise, I'd be obliged,
如果您在这房子里时
when you are in the house,
只呆在自己房间里
if you would keep to your room.
你妹妹Sarah 是她允许我的 女士
Your sister Sarah, gave me permission, Madame.
这是我家
This is my house,
不是我妹妹的
not my sister's.
就算她这么说了 当然我很怀疑
Even if she said it, which I doubt.
您怀疑我的话?
You doubt my word?
我会非常惊讶
I would be most surprised
如果我妹妹允许我的房客使用厨房
if my sister gave the run of the kitchen to my lodger.
你会惊讶令妹给了我什么
You would be surprised what your sister gives.
非常惊讶
Very surprised.
如果您现在能离开厨房
I think I would be obliged
我将十分感激 先生
if you left the kitchen now, Monsieur.
我觉得您没听到我在说什么
I don't think you hear what I'm saying?
Susan!
Marcel
Marcel.
噢 Susan
Oh Susan,
成功了
It has worked.
-他们让我当旅店的看守人 -现在你问问她她给了我什么
They have made me warden at the mission.
Now you ask her what she gave me.
是你给了Jacottet先生
Did you give Monsieur Jacottet
随意使用厨房的准许吗
permission to help himself in here,
in the kitchen?
我给过一次
I believe I did, once.
-我没想到他会... -问她
I didn't realize he'd...
你是什么意思 到底怎么回事
Ask her.
问她
What do you mean, what's going on?
Ask her!
你们英国人真是伪善
You English are such hypocrites.
你现在告诉她你给了我什么
Now you tell her what you gave me.
什么?
What?
这是怎么回事
What is all this about?
谁能告诉我到底怎么...
Will someone please tell me what's going...
我懂了
I see.
很好
Very well,
你现在是看守人了
you are warden now.
到那儿住去吧
Go and live there then.
你在旅店会有住处的
You'll have quarters at the mission.
去那儿
Go there.
我不想你留在我家
I don't want you under my roof.
走
Go.
我不会让你住在这儿
I won't have you here.
不会
I won't.
而你 先生
And as for you Monsieur,
你立刻离开我家
you will leave my house immediately.
立刻
Immediately.
不然我就叫警察
Or I will call the police.
你的行李将被打包后留在旁门那
Your belongings will be packed
and left at the tradesmen's entrance
你怎么敢
for your collection.
How dare you!
你简直和妈妈一模一样
You sound exactly like mother.
那又如何
And what if I do?
我还以为她过世后 自己再也不会
I thought I'd heard the last of that sort of thing
听到那样的话
when she died.
你怎敢如此说妈妈
How dare you talk about mother like that?
我像她有什么不好吗?
It's just as well I am like her.
不然我不知道我们家会发生什么
I don't know what would happen to this family otherwise.
你把我们都绑在你身边
Oh, you hold us all together do you.
你真伟大
How splendid you are.
你发现Mary不声不响
Do you realize that Mary has gone away
就离开了吗
without telling anyone?
好极了
Good.
她最终还是表现出了点勇气
She's showing some spirit at last.
你说这好极了?
You call that good?
有时候我觉得你不仅一事无成
Sometimes I think you're not just feckless,
而且故意推卸责任
I think you're deliberately irresponsible.
Mary已经结婚了
Mary is a married woman.
不是你的功劳
Well, no thanks to you.
你到最后都反对他们
You stood in her way to the last.
Jim Browner永远也不够资格
Jim Browner was never good enough
成为我们家一员 是吗
for our family was he?
Cushing少校的女儿们
The daughters of Major Cushing RE?
无所谓 他是个赌棍
Never mind, he was a gambling wastrel.
我们的父亲则是...
Our father was...
住口
Be quiet!
- 如果有谁让我们家蒙羞... - 那就是我
If anyone has disgraced this family it's me?
我警告你
I warn you,
总有一天这些责任
one day this diet of respectability
会让你自食其果
is going to make you ill.
你糟透了
You are so horrid.
-亲爱的Hudson夫人 -福尔摩斯先生
Ah dear Mrs. Hudson.
有个人和医生一起来了
Mr Holmes!
Susan Cushing小姐
The doctor has someone with him.
A Miss Susan Cushing.
知道了 请您拿好这个
Oh well, you'd better hold onto this.
这是什么
What's this?
那是什么
What's that?
是棵圣诞树
That is a Christmas tree,
一棵挪威云杉
it's a Norway spruce.
这位是Cushing小姐
This is Miss. Cushing.
Cushing小姐很担心她的妹妹Browner太太
Miss Cushing is concerned
about her sister, Mrs. Browner.
请继续
Pray continue.
Cushing小姐最小的妹妹和她住得并不远
Miss Cushing's youngest sister
就在东坎伯威尔
lives not far from her,
just east of Camberwell.
Browner太太每周五都来她家喝茶
Mrs. Browner visits her
除非她通知了不来 而这也很少发生
every Friday for tea,
unless she sends excuses,
which is most unusual.
上个星期五 19号
Last Friday the 19th,
Browner太太既未送来消息亦未到来
Mrs. Browner failed to send excuses or to arrive.
于是Cushing小姐询问了她的房客
So, Miss Cushing has made inquiries at her lodgings
但是Browner太太打上个礼拜四起
but Mrs. Browner has not been seen there
就不曾露面
since last Thursday.
听起来像是她失踪了
It sounds to me as though she has disappeared.
很显然 福尔摩斯
Evidently, Holmes.
她的失踪可能有一两个原因
There could be one or two reasons
我知道
for her disappearance.
要不就是她自己想失踪
Yes, I know.
要不就是有别的什么人希望她失踪
Either because she wished to disappear,
or because somebody else
你知道有什么原因
wished her to disappear.
可能使别人想让她消失吗
Do you know of any reason why
anyone else should wish her to disappear,
Mary?
没有
None.
她是最可爱的人儿
She is the most loveable of creatures.
人人都喜欢她
Everyone loves her.
至于她的下落 我建议
As to her whereabouts, I mean I suggest
您试试失踪人口处
that you try the missing peoples agency.
我给您一张地址单
I could find you a list of addresses.
好了 哈
There, hah.
真迷人 不是吗
Charming, isn't it?
对那棵云杉的小小改进
Slight improvement on that rather sad picea excelsa.
Sarah
Sarah.
Marcel
Marcel.
你被什么附身了吗?
What possessed you?
你把一切都搞砸了
You've wrecked it all.
我等不了了
The waiting possessed me.
你让我疯狂 Sarah
You drive me mad Sarah.
有时候我觉得我被附身了
Sometimes I think I am possessed.
你现在住哪
Where are you now?
医院附近的一个狗窝
Some filthy hole near the hospital.
都因为你姐姐
Thanks to your sister.
我不会让她忘记此事的
I will not let her forget this.
你需要一封介绍信
You'll need a reference
如果你想找个体面的住处的话
if you're going to find a decent place to stay.
圣诞节你要去比利时吗
Are you going to Belgium still for Christmas?
是的 我叔叔住在奥斯坦德附近
Yes.
你回来后 我会为你写一封介绍信
My uncle near Ostend.
Well, when you come back
I'll write a reference for you.
我现在是此处的看守
I'm Warden of this place.
它能算数
It'll count.
我爱你
I love you.
圣诞节以后来找我
Come to me after Christmas.
(knock on front door)
(knock on door)
是邮件 Cushin小姐
The post, Miss Cushing.
我把包裹放在树下好吗
Shall I put the parcels under the tree?
好的
Yes, please.
还是没有Browner太太的消息?
Nothing from Mrs. Browner, yet?
还是没有
Nothing as yet, no.
Sudgen店今天送的东西里有Madeira酒吗?
Did Sudgen's include the Madeira
是的 Cushing小姐
in their delivery today?
Yes, Miss Cushing.
今晚的一切都准备好了
Everything's ready for this evening.
谢谢
Thank you.
节日快乐 Bradbrook先生
Compliments of the season, Mr. Bradbrook.
非常感谢 您也是
Thank you very much,
and the very same to you.
Cushing小姐
Miss Cushing.
我说Cushing小姐
I say Miss Cushing.
抱歉
Sorry.
Bradbrook先生
Mr. Bradbrook?
我敢说您的妹妹 Sarah会来是吗
I dare say your sister, Sarah, will be joining us?
很遗憾她不来 Bradbrook先生
I am afraid not, Mr. Bradbrook.
她现在是Mission旅店的看守人
She is Warden of the Mission Hostel now
她有责任为了旅客留在那里
her duties to her residents will keep her there.
恐怕我只能
I shall see her
在周日见到她了
only on Sundays now I fear.
很遗憾让您失望了 Bradbrook先生
I'm sorry to disappoint you, Mr Bradbrook.
噢 不不不 您没有 一点也没
Oh no, no, no you haven't.
来吧 Bradbrook先生
Not at all, no.
今天是平安夜
Come now, Mr. Bradbrook.
It is Christmas Eve.
为了补偿您
To make up,
我们晚饭一结束
we shall open our presents
就来拆圣诞树下的礼物
from under the tree
而不必等到午夜
straight after supper
您说呢?
instead of at midnight.
很好 很好 太棒了
What do you say?
Very well.
Yes, yes, fine, splendid.
就这么做
Let's do that.
Gladstone最后会很开心的
Well, Gladstone will be pleased at least.
其中有一份是给它的礼物
There is a treat somewhere for him.
欢迎 先生们
Welcome gentlemen!
真高兴你们能来
Very good of you to come.
Gull 逮着他了?
Gull, has he been arrested?
没有 福尔摩斯先生
No, Mr. Holmes.
-他是来投诉的 -是吗?
He's come to complain.
他发现了我们在监视他
Has he indeed?
他不喜欢
He has spotted our surveillance of him,
你不会放弃?
and he doesn't like it.
当然不会
You won't give up?
Dear me, no.
好好玩吧
Join the party!
快点
Come on.
请进
(knock on door) Yes, come in.
噢 我亲爱的朋友
Oh, my dear fellow,
你穿上它了
you're wearing it.
我得试试
Well, I had to try it.
它最大的好处
What's so good about it
就是可以在车笼头前铺开
is that it stretches forward
如果你需要的话
over the handlebars if you need it.
你到底在哪儿发现的
Where on earth did you find it?
Gamages 百姓商场
Gamages, the people's Emporium.
谢谢
Thank you.
太棒了
Magnificent.
Hawkins 请进来吧 亲爱的朋友
Hawkins, do come in dear fellow.
请坐
Please, sit down.
盗墓贼又有什么新消息?
What is the news of the grave robberies?
坎伯威尔分局来了消息
The Camberwell force have been on to me.
那儿发生了一件意外
An incident down there.
他们怀疑两件事是否有关系
They were wondering if it had any connection?
我个人并不认为有
I don't think it does myself,
但我需要您的意见 福尔摩斯先生
but I'd value your opinion Mr. Holmes.
我们需要把这个下流的小玩笑
We need to get this nasty little joke
解决了处理掉
solved and out of the way.
玩笑?
Joke?
一位尊敬的女士
Respectable lady,
在平安夜和朋友们一起
in company opening her parcels,
拆开她的包裹
Christmas Eve.
其中一件有点奇怪
One of them's a bit odd.
装满了盐
It's full of salt.
她把盐倒光
She empties out the salt.
里面是什么?
What's in it?
两只刚切下来的人耳
Two freshly severed human ears.
我们认为是个医学院学生干的
We think it was a medical student.
她曾有个房客是医学院学生
She had a medical student as a lodger.
解剖系学生可以
Post-mortem anatomy can make
轻而易举的做到
certain individuals thoroughly callous.
她在圣诞节前把他赶出来
She threw him out just before Christmas.
显然有些争吵
Bit of a row, apparently.
无论如何 因为我知道您的办案方法 福尔摩斯先生
Anyway, knowing your methods, Mr. Holmes,
我把耳朵原封不动 留在那位女士的家里
I've had the ears left quite untouched
at the lady's house.
就在
Which is,
Trafalgar Villa 坎波维尔
yes here it is, Trafalgar Villa, Camberwell.
一位Susan Cushing小姐
A Miss Susan Cushing.
福尔摩斯先生
Oh, Mr. Holmes.
您终于来帮我找Mary了吗
Have you come to help me find Mary after all?
我很抱歉 Cushing小姐
I'm afraid not, Miss Cushing.
警督请我来
The Inspector has asked me
查另一单不幸的案件
to look into that other unfortunate business.
噢 那个
Oh, that.
Hawkins先生 我不会把东西放在这里
Well, I won't have those things in the house Mr. Hawkins.
如果您想看看的话
If you wish to see them,
您得去温室
you must go to the conservatory.
那个不幸的年轻人被逮住了没
Have you arrested that wretched young man yet?
只是时间问题 Cushing小姐
Just a matter of time, Miss Cushing.
Harwich的邮戳
Postmark Harwich.
Jacottet这个学生现在
Now this student fellow Jacottet
在回家过圣诞节
was going home for Christmas
从Harwich去往Ostend
to Ostend via Harwich.
是的 我同意
Yes, I agree,
Harwich能说明这点
Harwich is persuasive.
字迹很差
The writing is poor.
未受过教育
Uneducated.
我知道医疗行业的人
I know the medical profession
字迹都很潦草 但是这个...
is notorious for this illegibility, but this...
用粗头钢笔写的
done with a broad nibbed pen,
墨水很差
very inferior ink.
涂过柏油的麻绳
Tarred twine.
斯德哥尔摩柏油
Stockholm tar.
结绳原封未动
Knots intact.
粗盐
Rock salt...
埋在里面的是...
and embedded in it...
这些特殊的东西
these very singular enclosures.
你怎么看 华生
What do you think of it, Watson?
这个耳朵穿过耳洞
A ring has been torn from this ear.
不是一对
They're not a pair.
Jacottet从解剖室
I supposed it would be rather easier for Jacottet
很容易挑两只
to have abstracted the ears from a dissecting room
不成对的耳朵
which were not actually a pair.
为什么?
To what purpose?
某种恶作剧
Some kind of disgusting practical joke.
这不是恶作剧
Gentlemen, this is no practical joke.
当你进入解剖室里
What first strikes you
首先察觉到的是什么?
when you enter a dissecting room?
甲醛
Formaldehyde.
该死 应该能问到甲醛味
Dammit, it should smell of formaldehyde.
但是这个没有
And it does not.
这不是恶作剧
This is no practical joke.
这是严重的犯罪
This is a serious crime.
(knock on door)
你妹妹 Cushing小姐
Your sister, Miss Cushing.
Mary
Mary.
终于来了
At last.
"玛丽 玛丽 十分叛逆" (一首民谣)
Mary, Mary, quite contrary.
我以为是Mary
I thought it was Mary.
我来拿我的东西
I've come to take some more of my things.
我们吵架之前我给你买了个礼物
I bought you a present before we argued.
你还是收下吧
You may as well have it.
我不想要
I don't want it.
你怎么了
What's the matter with you?
又是什么恶心的玩笑吗
Is it another disgusting prank?
什么
What?
毕竟他是你的朋友
Well, he was your friend, after all.
谁
Who was?
我不想要你的恐怖包裹
I don't want your horrid parcel.
拿去 保留一点礼仪吧 姐姐
Take it.
Let's preserve the proprieties at least, Sister.
礼仪?
Proprieties?
你敢谈礼仪?
You dare to talk about the proprieties?
你一生都在破坏社会规范
You have flouted the rules of society all your life.
而你还敢厚颜无耻的指责我
And you had the effrontery to accuse me
阻止Mary嫁给那个男人
of interfering with Mary's marrying that man.
难道不是?
Didn't you?
但是你干了什么
But what did you do?
我干了什么
What did I do?
我什么也没干
I did nothing.
你心知肚明
You know what you did.
你给Mary介绍了别的男人
You introduced Mary to other men.
带坏她
Corrupting her.
Mary告诉了我她的无辜
Mary has told me in her innocence.
她责怪我?
She accused me?
Mary从不责怪任何人
Mary accuses no one.
你知道
You know that.
但我知道你给她带来了不幸
But I see your hand in her unhappiness.
胡说
Nonsense.
为什么Jim Browner又开始酗酒
Why did Jim Browner start drinking again?
他对Mary发过誓
He signed the pledge for Mary.
因此他们在才一起的
That's what brought them together.
她把蓝色丝带别在他胸前
She pinned the blue ribbon to his chest
他已经重新做人了
and he was a new man.
为什么他打破他的誓言?
So why did he break his pledge?
为什么问我?
Why ask me?
你为什么和他吵架
Why did you quarrel with him?
我从来不赞成Jim Browner 这是事实
I never approved of Jim Browner, that's true.
但他不应该因为你的多事 而重新酗酒
But he deserved better
than being driven back to drink by your meddling.
我回来了
I'm back.
Jim
Jim.
你好 Sarah
Hello Sarah.
Mary没想到你会这么早回来
Mary wasn't expecting you till much later.
我赶上了尾潮
I managed to catch the tail end of the flood.
节约了一次潮汐的时间
Saved a whole tide.
她不在家?
She not here then?
不
No.
Cooper老奶奶又不舒服了
Old Mrs. Cooper's not well again.
Mary在陪她
Mary's with her.
我说我会来帮她洗衣服
I said I'd help her with the laundry.
她马上就回来
She'll be back soon.
你帮了她很多 不是吗
You help her a lot, don't you?
真好
That's nice.
我猜你知道我为什么帮她?
You know why I help her, I suppose?
什么
What?
为什么我老在这儿
Why I am always round here?
你是她姐姐
You're her sister.
她不在身边五分钟 你都会不高兴 是吗 Jim?
Can't you be happy for five minutes without her, Jim?
来
Here,
帮帮忙
make yourself useful.
然后放下这一边
Drop the side then.
什么
What?
你放下这个
Well you drop this
然后拿起另一边
and bring it up the other side.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
Mary不这么做
Mary doesn't do that.
我敢说 Mary不做的事情多着呢
There are plenty of things Mary doesn't do,
I dare say.
我来教你怎么做
Look, I'll show you how to do it, shall I?
现在
Now.
过来
Now come on.
你拿着这个角
You take this corner.
好 现在...
Right.
你放下这个...
Now,
you drop this...
然后...
and...
你拿起这个
you bring it up,
另一边
the other side.
你自己来
You do it yourself.
这不是我做的 我可不要
That's not for me.
I want no part of that.
把女人的工作塞给我
Pushing women's work at me.
你自己去做吧
You keep that to yourself.
福尔摩斯先生和另一位先生来看你 夫人
Mr. Holmes, and the other gentlemen to see you madam.
让他们别把那些东西带进来
As long as they don't bring those things near me.
他现在在哪
And where is he now?
Browner和Mary结婚时
Mr. Browner was on the South American line
在跑南美航线
when he and Mary married.
但他太爱她了
But he was so fond of her,
于是他转到
that he found himself a berth
北海航船上
in the North Sea boats.
跑伦敦-登荷德航线
The London - Den Helder line.
Mary爱他吗
And is Mary fond of him?
他们是恋爱结婚
It was a love match.
恋爱?
Love?
尽管...
Although...
什么?
Yes?
当时我不愿意承认这个事实
I was loathed to acknowledge it at the time.
为什么
Why was that?
我觉得我的姐妹
I didn't think a sister of mine
不该嫁给一个船员
should be marrying a steward.
现在呢
And now?
您现在感觉如何
How do you feel now?
我想Jim和Mary本可以幸福
I think Jim and Mary could be happy.
您的意思是他们并不幸福?
You mean they weren't?
一开始是的
They were at first.
然后呢
What happened?
也许你该问问Sarah
Perhaps you should ask Sarah.
她在那里住过一阵子
She practically lived there for a while.
现在Browner先生在哪条船上?
Which ship is Mr. Browner serving with at present?
"五朔节"号
The "May Morning".
17号启程
She sailed on the 17th
开往比利时和荷兰
for Belgium and Holland.
圣诞节他们在鹿特丹
They were in Rotterdam over Christmas.
船员抽签
The crews draw lots
Jim今年运气不好
and Jim was unlucky this year.
Mary得和我和Sarah一起过圣诞节
Mary was to have spent Christmas with Sarah and me.
而现在Sarah
And now Sarah, of course,
在旅店做看守人
is Warden at the mission.
您是否不让她和您住一起?
Are you sad not to have her living with you still?
是的
Yes I am.
实话告诉你吧 福尔摩斯先生
Well to tell you the truth, Mr. Holmes,
我们俩相处得不好
things are not well between us.
你们吵架了?
You've quarreled?
为了什么?
What about?
也许会和你妹妹
It may have a bearing
Mary的失踪有关系
on what has happened to your sister Mary.
我知道
I know that.
当然有关
Of course it does.
你以为我不知道吗
Do you think I don't know that?
我认为一切都是她的错
I blame her for everything.
Sarah?
当然
Of course.
Sarah
Sarah.
她老呆在Mary家
She spent far more time than was necessary
完全没有这个必要
at Mary's lodgings.
Jim和Mary才新婚
Jim and Mary were just married,
过着自己的新生活
making their own life,
结交新朋友
making their own friends.
而Sarah给他们介绍了Alec Fairbairn
Then Sarah introduced Alec Fairbairn to them.
我知道这不是好意
I know it was not generously done.
看起来Sarah是想羞辱Jim Browner
Sarah seemed to want to shame Jim Browner.
我不知道Jim对Sarah做了什么
I don't know what Jim had done to Sarah,
但好像她恨他
but she seemed to hate him.
我相信...
I believe that...
你相信什么
You believe what?
问她
Ask her.
问Sarah
Ask Sarah.
她在这里收拾她的东西
She is here in the house collecting her things.
问她是不是想让Mary
Ask her if she did not mean Mary
和Alec Fairbairn私奔
to go off with Alec Fairbairn.
这就是她的目的
That is what she wanted.
我知道
I know it.
她已经收到消息了
Ah, the message has been received then.
咖啡? 先生
Caf? Monsieur.
谢谢你的帮助 警督
Thank you for your help, Inspector.
这很难 福尔摩斯先生
It's very difficult Mr. Holmes.
我们不能忽视证据
We can't ignore the evidence,
我们知道了什么?
what've we got?
包裹里的两只耳朵
Two severed ears in a parcel.
我们知道一个医学院学生Jacottet
We've got the medical student, Jacottet
他被赶出了这位女士的家
who's been thrown out of the lady's house.
强烈的动机
Strong motive.
包裹是19号从Harwich寄出的
Parcel postmarked Harwich on the 19th.
他19号也在Harwich
He was in Harwich on the 19th.
只有这么多了
That's as good as you get.
你的推理很浅显易懂 Hawkins
Your logic seems foolproof Hawkins.
谢谢
Thank you.
遗憾的是我不能阻止此事登报
I just regret that I haven't been able
他们正在为明早的头版写这个报道
to keep it out of the newspapers.
They're running the story
他们也得到了Susan Chusing小姐的名字
in tomorrow morning's first edition.
They've also managed to get hold of
她不会喜欢这样的
Miss Susan Cushing's name.
可怜的女人
She won't like that.
Poor woman.
那么另一件案子 福尔摩斯先生
This other matter then, Mr. Holmes.
你也有想法了 是吧?
You've clearly got some thoughts on that,
haven't you?
我相信
It is my belief,
某位华生医生的同行
that a member of Dr Watson's profession,
为了某种目的铤而走险
possibly of some distinction,
has overstepped the mark.
所有尸体都是拳击手的
The corpses all belong to pugilists,
业余或者其他的
amateur or otherwise.
搏斗太久的拳击手
What is the unfortunate characteristic of boxers
有什么不幸的特征?
who have fought too long?
他们的脑部会留下很多创伤
Well, there can be such scarring of the brain
会像喝醉了酒似的
that they behave as if they're drunk,
说话含糊
slurred speech,
记忆缺失或者其他
loss of memory and so on.
他们变得头昏眼花
They become punch drunk.
正是如此
Precisely.
您是说有人在研究
You mean somebody is studying
脑部组织病理学?
the pathology of brain tissues?
我认为正是如此
For all the best reasons, I dare say.
他们研究的热情
And their passion for their subject
超过了他们的理性
has outrun their judgment.
Marcus Lanyon爵士
Sir Marcus Lanyon,
我赌一个月的工资是Marcus爵士
I'll wager a month's salary on Sir Marcus.
这正是他的专业
That's precisely his specialty
他没有耐心
and he is impatient to a fault,
冷血无情
ruthlessly impatient.
现在你知道了 警督
There you have it, Inspector.
(knock on door)
她很沮丧
She is very down.
下午她回来以后
Like this ever since
就一直这样
she got back here this afternoon.
Cushing小姐?
Miss Cushing?
你和你的妹夫Browner先生
Why did you quarrel
为何事争吵
with your brother-in-law, Mr. Browner?
什么
What?
你是谁 为何在此
Who are you, what are you doing here?
这位是歇洛克 福尔摩斯
This is Sherlock Holmes,
他正在调查你的妹妹
he is investigating the disappearance
Mary的失踪案
of you sister, Mary.
她和Alec Fairbairn跑了 就是这样
She's gone off with Alec Fairbairn that's all.
为什么?
Why?
她被她丈夫吓坏了
She had become frightened of her husband.
为什么
Why?
Jim Browner是个酒鬼
Jim Browner was a drunkard.
他打她
He offered her violence.
为人卑劣
He was beneath contempt.
你对这对耳朵作何解释
What is your explanation for the severed ears,
Cushing小姐
Miss Cushing?
你见过那个硬纸盒子了
You saw that cardboard box.
在你姐姐家
At your sister's house.
那对耳朵是给你的 不是吗
Those severed ears were meant for you were they not?
这个信息是给你的
The message was for you.
你知道它们意味着什么
You understood what they meant.
是Marcel Jacottet寄来的
Marcel Jacottet sent them.
他告诉我他会做些什么
He told me he might do something.
我没想到他会做这么恶心的事儿
I didn't realize he'd do anything so disgusting.
她在说谎 华生
She's lying, Watson.
她在空口说白话
She's lying through her teeth.
Gull在外面
Gull's outside.
太棒了
Excellent.
我去过航线办公室了
I've been to the shipping line offices too.
然后?
And?
正如你所认为
It's as you thought.
"五朔节"号于17号从伦敦出发
The "May Morning" set sail from London
驶往登荷德
for Den Helder on the 17th,
但是一个大桶松开了
but a hogshead got loose in her hold.
使一个横梁脱了节
She sprang a plate,
必须进港维修
and had to put in for repairs.
在Harwich?
To Harwich?
To Harwich.
船员18号放假
The crew were given leave on the 18th.
"五朔月"号在19号晚启程
The "May Morning" left late on the 19th,
就是包裹寄出的同一天
the day the parcel was posted.
太棒了 华生
Excellent Watson.
有答案了
We have it.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr Holmes.
Gull先生
Mr. Gull.
他们来了电报
They have telegraphed.
Jim Browner今晚7点
Jim Browner came off the ferry at Ramsgate
在Ramsgate下船
at seven o'clock this evening.
很好
Good.
我就知道我可以信任您
I knew I could rely on you.
我可以信任您吗
And I can rely on you, can I?
你能
You can.
Marcus Lanyon爵士这个名字
Does the name,
对你有什么意义吗
Sir Marcus Lanyon mean anything to you?
可能有
It might.
他会得到警告
He will be warned off.
您从中获利的工作将结束
And the orders from which you have been profiting will dry up
同样警察对您的兴趣也会随之消失
but so will the police interest in you.
我很满意这个结果
I'll be satisfied with that.
我们谈了笔好买卖 Gull先生
We've acquired a bargain, Mr. Gull.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
等等
Hold on.
包裹上的绳结
The knots on the parcel
是单套结和接绳结
were a bowline and a sheet bend.
是的 水手结
Yes, sailors knots.
你知道水手们一般
You know that sailors deliberately
不会磨刀
do not sharpen their knives.
是的 除非有事故
Yes, in case of accidents.
因此这个残忍的切割
Hence the crude amputations.
Harwich是关键
Harwich was the key
而Browner当时在那儿
and Browner was there.
现在我推测
Now, I suppose,
Browner意外回到家中
Browner returned unexpectedly,
发现他妻子和Fairbairn在一起
found his wife with Fairbairn.
他尾随他们
He followed them.
杀害了他们
He murdered them both.
各切下他们一人的耳朵
He severed an ear from each
然后寄给Sarah Cushing
and sent them as he thought to Sarah Cushing.
当然他会立刻到那里
Of course, he will go there immediately.
他等不及要告诉她
He will be desperate for her to know
那两只耳朵是给她的
that the severed ears were for her,
而非给她姐姐
and not for her sister.
就是这样
Well, that being the case,
现在周日也有火车
the railway is operating
as if it were a Sunday.
为什么
Why?
因为还是圣诞期间
Because the Christmas holiday is still on.
你有没有意识到Browner 可能搭更早的火车?
Do you realize,
Browner could have caught a much earlier train.
不 我没有
No, I did not know.
Mary
Mary.
这是什么 福尔摩斯先生
What is this, Mr. Holmes?
一次你的特殊经历 警督
A unique experience for you, Inspector?
你或许能在知道一桩谋杀发生之前
You may apprehend a murderer
就抓到一个凶杀
before you have even acknowledged
there has been a murder.
是的
Aye.
你惊讶吧
Well you may stare.
看着我 Sarah Cushing
Look at me, Sarah Cushing,
这是你的拿手好戏
this is your handy work.
你做了什么 Jim?
What have you done, Jim?
我做了什么?
What have I done?
是你做了什么
Aye, it's what you've done.
我求求你
I beg you, Jim,
好好看着我
look on me kindly.
我做的一切
Whatever I did,
都是为了你
I did for you.
是你
It was you.
是你毒害了她的思想
You poisoned her mind.
我这么做是为了你
I did it for you.
他们抓住了那个房客
They have arrested the lodger.
我告诉他们是他做的
I told them he did it.
他们丝毫没有怀疑你 Jim
They suspect nothing of you, Jim.
你可以逃脱
You can get away.
逃脱?
Get away?
你以为我能逃脱
You think I can get away.
当一切没发生过
Put it all behind me,
你这么以为 不是吗
you think, do you,
你疯了
are you mad.
是我
It is me.
就在这儿
It's in here.
每一幕每一幕
Every last moment of it.
每天都在我面前
It comes out of the daylight at me,
不断重现
it goes on and on.
自打犯案起 我不敢闭着眼睛睡觉
I tell you I dare not shut an eye in sleep
我不敢一个人呆着
since I did it.
I'm never without one or the other before me.
愿你的血在你的血管里腐败
May the blood rot in your veins, Sarah Cushing.
不 不
No, no.
我爱你
I love you,
I love you.
我爱你
I love you,
-我爱你 -我相信
I love you.
I believe you do.
我告诉你
I tell you something,
我宁愿从被我杀死的她口中听到一个字
I'd rather have one kind word
也不要你的爱
from her I've killed than all your love.
我宁愿看着她多呼吸一分钟
I'd rather see her breathing one minute more
也不要你给我一辈子
than a lifetime of what you could give me.
别这么说 别这么说
Don't say that,
don't say that,
don't say that.
她爱我
She loved me.
这就是一切的根源
That's the root of the business.
但是她知道
But she knew,
她知道
she knew,
她知道我
she knew I,
我想到我泥地里的脚印
I thought more about my footprint in the mud
多于想到她的身体和灵魂
than I did of her body and soul.
做梦也没想到啊
Where would I have dreamt it?
在拒绝了Sarah的殷勤之后
And after he had rejected Sarah's advances.
我一个字也没对Mary说
I never said a word to Mary
我想这会让她难过
for I thought it would grieve her.
然后我发现Mary开始变了
Then I began to see a change in Mary herself.
我妻子一向
My wife had always been
善解人意
sort of understanding.
现在她对一切都怀疑
Now she's suspicious of everything I did.
我们开始无谓的争吵
We began to row about nothing,
完全没有原因
nothing at all.
这让我发狂
It maddened me.
事实也是如此吗?
And this was said as well?
是的 不是我瞎想
Aye, I didn't say it then mind,
我只是看到一切都不对了
I just saw it all go wrong.
她和Mary形影不离
She and Mary were inseparable and then,
后来我开了戒 又开始酗酒
well then I broke my blue ribbon
and begun drinking again
所以Mary有理由讨厌我了
so Mary had some reason
to be disgusted with me now.
然后这个Fairbairn就插进来了
And then this Fairbairn fellow chipped in.
他是个时髦浮华的小伙子
He was a dashing, swaggering sort of a chap,
聪明 长着一头卷发
smart and curled,
还受过教育
educated too,
我认为他很健谈
I reckon he could talk, he could.
是一件小事
But I know it was,
使我产生了疑虑
it was a little thing put me on to em.
我那天偶尔来到客厅
I came into the parlor unexpected one day
一进门
and as I came in
我看见我妻子眼睛里闪过欢迎的光
I saw the light of welcome in me wife's eyes
但当她发现是我时
but when she saw it was me
她带着失望的表情转身就走了
she turned away with a look of disappointment.
肯定是把我当成Alec Fairbairn了
There was no one but Alec Fairbairn
不会是别人
whose steps you can mistake from mine.
从那一刻起我的平静就一去不复返了
I tell you from that moment on my peace was gone.
Sarah当时在厨房
Sarah was in the kitchen
我直接走进厨房 告诉她
and I went straight through, and I told her
如果Fairbairn再出现在我家
that if Fairbairn ever set foot in my place again
我就把他的耳朵留给你做纪念
I'd send her his ears for a keepsake.
我希望你是在法国犯下这个案子
I believe I could wish you had
committed this deed of yours in France.
他们承认冲动犯罪
They acknowledge the crime of passion there.
你不会让他们把我单独留在这
You won't let them leave me alone,
是吗 先生
will you, sir?
不
No,
我不会
I won't.
我走的时候会叫个警官进来
When I leave I'll send an officer in.
我不想一个人
I don't like to be alone, see.
到你了
Your turn.
(knock on door)
我去去就来
Won't be a minute.
她让事情变糟的 是吗
She made it go wrong, didn't she?
你心里从来都只有我
And you never thought of anyone but me,
是吗 Jim?
did you, Jim?
她爱你
She loved you
她让我恨你
and she made me hate you.
看起来似乎她有什么秘密
There, it was as if she had a secret you see,
她让我往最坏处想
she made me think the worst.
这个秘密就是她爱我?
The secret was her loving me?
你该让她远离我们的生活 Jim
You should've got rid of her from our lives, Jim.
我知道
I know,
我知道那会伤害你
I thought it would hurt you.
看看我们现在
Look at us now,
我真傻
I was stupid,
真是瞎了眼
blind as a beetle.
这是什么意思 华生
What is the meaning of it, Watson?
这一连串的...
What is the object of this
痛苦 暴力和恐惧究竟是为了什么
circle of misery, and violence, and fear?
一定有某种目的
It must have a purpose,
不然我们这个宇宙就毫无意义
or our universe has no meaning
而这是无法想象的
and that is unthinkable.
但是是什么目的呢
But what purpose?
这是人类的大问题
That is humanity's great problem
思索了多少年
for which reasons so far
也没有答案
there's no answer.
全剧终
风软FRM字幕组作品 -==http://www.1000fr.com==- 欢迎加入